Gentle-hearted gay man Genichi Hatano
and his partner, Saku Sakuta,
struggles to find a home
to serve as a "clamp."
Hotaru has finally found a dream
in making guitars,
but their fake relationship
is discovered by the police,
and she’s sent to a child guidance center.
Meanwhile, Hotaru’s mother, Tomoe,
had her bag stolen,
along with all her keychains.
Her dad, Jin Ichigaya, though,
has made off with the 30 million
from Genichi’s apartment.
It’s gone! The 30 million yen…
Stop following me!
This is a crime!
- You’re gonna get arrested!
- Shut up!
Hey!
- Coming through!
- Watch out!
Get out of our way!
Huh?
Hey!
Where did he go?
Where are you?
Hold it right there!
Red means stop.
You seem to be on the run.
What?
May I check what's inside?
No.
- Let me see it.
- I said no!
Do you have any sort of ID on you?
I’m not a suspicious person.
Here you go.
JIN ICHIGAYA
- Mr. Jin Ichigaya.
- That's right.
And your ex-wife’s name is Tomoe Kusunoki?
Your daughter’s name is Hotaru Kusunoki?
‪What?
If this little one is here,
then he must be the one who did it.
He's not picking up.
Everything is exposed,
and on top of that,
the 30 million was stolen?
I didn’t lock up properly.
I’m really sorry.
It’s just 30 million yen.
Don’t have to apologize.
"Just"?
The one at fault is my dad.
And the one who embezzled is my mom.
You don’t have to force yourself.
I'm not though.
Sorry to interrupt.
Did you forget something?
No. Hotaru?
Yes?
Please come out already.
What?
After stopping by here,
I questioned this man.
He goes by the name Jin Ichigaya,
so I thought he might be Hotaru’s dad
and brought him here.
He’s not my dad.
He’s a thief.
A thief?
No, I'm not!
Please give that back!
What? Does it belong to you, Mr. Sakuta?
Well, uh…
It’s mine. Mine. It’s mine!
But it's not, right?
In any case, he’s not my dad.
Is that right?
- That’s a shame.
- What?
If your real dad were here,
then we won’t need to question you
or report this to the school
or child guidance center.
Really?
- Oh?
- Oh my!
Truly unfortunate.
Looking closely, he is my dad.
Huh?
He's my dad after all.
- What's this all of a sudden?
- Dad!
W-What is it?
Why have you been leaving her
alone all this time?
Hotaru has been living here by herself,
asking strangers to pretend
to be her parents!
- She's the one wh--
- I just didn’t contact him!
Are you willing to take care
of Hotaru from now on?
- Uh…
- Yes.
I think he will, right?
Play along, or I’ll tell her you stole it.
What will it be?
I’ll take care of her.
As her father,
I’ll properly look after Hotaru.
Are you sure this is okay?
Thank you so much for bringing him here.
Okay.
- That's great to hear.
- Yes!
Yeah, good for her.
What?
Did you two manage to make up?
Ah! Well, yeah.
I’ll consider the situation
resolved for now.
From here on, please look after
Hotaru as her neighbors.
- Okay.
- I’m trusting you on this.
- Thank you.
I'll excuse myself.
- After looking closely, you're not my dad.
- Huh?
Please give that back.
- I don't wanna!
- Give it back!
I said no!
Then give me back my rabbit!
Stop aiming for my lower body!
- Stop--
- I'll be taking that from you.
Excuse me!
- Yes?
- The 30 million…
The money my mom embezzled.
What happens if the total was returned
without any of it being used?
- Do you have the 30 million with you?
- Oh, no.
Just hypothetically speaking.
I’m not sure of the exact verdict,
but chances of a lighter sentence
or a reprieve would likely increase,
I believe.
Is that right?
You sure you don’t want me
to call the police?
Yeah.
I’m fine, really.
There's no need for the police.
But your bag…
There wasn’t anything important in it.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
The person who stole them
might be freaking out now
with all the keychains spilling out.
If you're fine with that. Wait here, okay?
DRAFT BEER
Here's a little freebie!
Thank you.
Cheer up.
My wallet was in my pocket.
Then you can get home!
Yes.
I’m… going home.
Oh, come on!
- Please give it back!
- It’s not your money!
It’s not yours either!
- Give it back!
- Give it back?
It’s embezzled cash!
- What?
- I was safekeeping it!
So, it’s mine for now!
We guarded it together,
so it’s mine too!
That’s right! We’re in this together!
Accomplice?
Why are you so obsessed wi--
Because I can't bear to give them up!
A big car…
with my wife and daughter…
and my parents and a big dog…
Everyone together at the beach.
And by doing this…
Taking off my sunglasses and looking cool…
That’s a man’s happiness!
So, this time…
I’m gonna do things right…
Oh, why are you here?
Oh, um… I saw him
running away with the suitcase
and chased him but lost him,
so I came back here,
and well, this is where I am.
I see. Thanks.
So, about this money…
You were all hiding the embezzled cash
the entire time?
Well, yeah.
If we return it unused,
Mom might not get arrested.
That police officer said so.
Are you hungry?
Huh?
Do you have somewhere warm to sleep?
Don't worry. You can stay here tonight.
As if I'm gonna stay
in this rundown place!
Good luck sleeping on the streets then.
What?
Here.
Eat up and have some hot tea.
We still haven’t gotten
the money back though.
He’s too cowardly
to actually spend it.
I sure hope that's the case.
You’re not calling the police?
- Hey!
- I won't call them, okay?
But… Wow.
Pretending to be a parent is already bad,
but hiding embezzled money too?
You guys are absolutely insane.
Sorry.
I'm such a bore, aren't I?
What?
I don’t think I’m in the wrong here.
But still, it’s boring, I guess?
What's gotten into you? Are you alright?
Yeah.
Looking at animals helps.
- Huh?
- When you’re down.
I'm not exactly feeling down, though.
Sorry.
I'm taking my leave.
Okay, that’s it for today.
- Okay.
Right after New Year’s, we have
the final parent teacher meeting.
You’ll be making your final decisions
about your career paths,
so make sure to discuss things
with your guardians.
WRITTEN NOTICE
With that said, I’ll hand out the notices.
- What now.
- Want some?
New Year’s soba?
It’s still early for that, no?
If you don’t want it, that’s fine.
- I’ll eat it.
- Here you go.
Huh?
What the hell is this? It's all in lumps.
The landlady's handmade soba.
It used to be her hobby.
Camping was also her hobby,
so she has this tent.
She didn’t stick with either though.
Do you want the money that badly?
Yeah.
A man’s gotta have heaps of cash.
What?
NAKAYOSHI PLAZA
Oh, welcome!
Because you said I should look at animals.
Ah, right.
It's not that I’m not feeling low, okay!
Got it.
NAKAYOSHI PLAZA
Why does looking at animals help
when I'm feeling low?
Because they all live however they want.
It’s encouraging.
Really?
Some run around,
some stay still.
Some stick together,
some play alone.
They are all different, but all cute.
You kind of live
however you want too, Hatano.
What, me?
I wonder how you manage to do that.
Is there something you want to do?
I don’t know.
Maybe observe really closely?
Our landlady said that
when she draws, if she really observes,
she starts noticing all sorts of things.
So, maybe you should
really observe yourself?
And I mean with your eyes.
Really observe, with your very own eyes.
Well then.
ANIMALS ILLUSTRATION CONTEST
It’s a joint contest
run by all zoos in Tokyo.
When I gave this to the landlady earlier,
she said she’s aiming for the grand prize!
Done.
Should I be going
to the parent-teacher meeting?
The contract lasts until graduation.
Well, that's true.
What about your career plans?
Have you decided on what exactly?
- Well…
- Come on now…
- Welcome back.
I'm back.
- Is that osechi?
- Yeah, I pre-ordered it.
But more importantly, something
even more exciting is coming, right?
Don't get ahead of yourself.
About your house?
After New Year's,
we’re going to the property agency.
Have you decided on the type of house?
One that proves our love has meaning.
We want that kind of house.
One that will serve as a "clamp."
A house of "love and revolution."
What kind of house is that?
Somewhere in Tokyo, around this area,
under 55 million yen,
a home we can live long-term,
that retains its value,
is no more than ten years old,
at least 50 square meters,
has proper privacy,
and a neighborhood
we can get along with well.
That’s specific.
INOKASHIRA APARTMENTS
It’s time for the harvest.
Here we go.
Amazing!
So, that's…
the happiness a man
is unable to give up on?
Why do you care?
It’s cold outside, right?
You can use a room if you want.
After the New Year,
I’ll find a place and move out.
Here, a homemade New Year’s osechi
from the landlady.
GREAT LUCK
Happy New Year.
- Usami. Wanna eat?
- You named it Usami?
What do you guys call it then?
I haven’t thought about it.
What about Usamaru?
- Usamaru?
Alone…
but not lonely!
GOAL THIS YEAR: ALONE, BUT NOT LONELY!
I can do it.
- Happy New Year!
- Happy New Year.
- The prize money is 300,000 yen?
- Yeah, and I want this.
That's cool.
What are you gonna draw?
- An animal, duh.
- What kind?
Are there animals around here?
Animals, huh.
I see how it is.
Observe closely, huh?
As for one that meets all your conditions,
we don’t quite have it right now.
You only have one job!
Well…
If you don’t mind paying a bit more…
I do mind.
Or a smaller place?
I said no!
Welcome!
We’ve been expecting you.
Please have a seat.
What's with that look?
Please come by again
with updated conditions.
- Sorry for the inconvenience.
- Geez.
Alright. So…
I found a few promising properties.
If you like any,
we can schedule a viewing.
- Okay!
- Please do.
Great.
First, this one.
48 MILLION YEN
Within your budget, 48 million.
Fifty square meters and 2LDK.
Built 55 years ago,
but it's refurbished inside.
A vintage house?
I was hoping for something
that could hold its value, you know?
If you want to prioritize asset value…
Here’s another option.
Sixty square meters,
two minutes from the station,
and only ten years old.
Seventy million, though…
For both of you, the monthly repayment
would be around 200,000 yen.
Manageable if you budget carefully.
Sounds good. You two
could handle a modest life.
But life would get pretty tight then, no?
If we want to prioritize budget?
This is a 20-year-old house.
Forty-four point eight million.
- Where is this?
- Saitama prefecture.
It’s going to take a while
to get to work then.
Just commuting alone will wear you out.
And it’s 20 years old, huh?
Sorry, I forgot to ask.
What are your priorities?
Longevity? Investment value?
Size? Privacy?
Since we’re buying a house,
I want a good one
that meets our conditions.
Same here. I don’t want
to compromise too much.
Well then, could you all
come with me for a moment?
- Um, how much longer--
- Please don’t move!
Sorry.
- Hello!
- Hello.
- Huh?
Hello.
- Who are you?
- Our model.
- What model?
- This.
She just happened to be passing by.
- Sorry about this.
- Ah, it’s fine.
I just came on my lunch break
to buy some roasted sweet potatoes
and I got scouted.
I scouted her.
Wait, are you even supposed
to draw humans?
ANIMALS ILLUSTRATION CONTEST
Are you a school teacher?
Are they your students?
I’m with Nikomado
from the Niko Consultation Desk.
My name is Koito.
We’re all from different schools.
This is the only place we meet.
But we’re really good friends.
You too, Koinobori. Don't you agree?
We're friends?
Are we not?
You're not wrong.
Are you guys keeping up?
Is there a nice property
up ahead or something?
- Are we there yet?
- Hey!
- You've got to be picking on us, no?
- Sorry.
We're almost there.
Nice view!
You're right.
I like it here. Sometimes
I come up to take a breather.
See that brown apartment
along the main street?
- The huge one?
- Right.
The people living there
stretched their finances
to buy a condo over their budget.
But
the side job they started
to make ends meet
ended up doing better than their main job.
Really?
And that house
with the orange roof over there.
It's near a park,
so bugs sometimes get into the rooms,
but in autumn, you can hear the crickets,
and they enjoy the seasonal charm.
That condo over there has thin walls,
but they say it makes them
feel less alone,
so they can binge horror movies
even when alone.
Okay?
So, why drag us all the way here?
Because… Listen,
I get wanting ideal conditions
and not wanting to compromise.
But giving something up…
isn’t always a bad thing.
That's what I wanted to convey.
It's the same with our place.
It’s pretty old,
and honestly, it’s falling apart.
The rooms are cramped,
the washing machine is outside,
and the stairs break too.
Don’t roast that place too hard.
But we get to live with animals,
the landlady is funny,
and I met Hotaru there.
And Sakuta.
Is that our place?
What?
Isn't that the complete
opposite direction?
Nah, it’s this way. I'm sure of it.
Okay, done!
I forgot the ring.
I see now…
I wanted to take it off all along.
BODYWORK & PAINT
250,400 YEN
Thank you, miss!
- Thanks!
Don’t mention it.
Get home safe!
- Okay!
- Bye!
How awesome are we?
It was fun being a model for them.
They’re all pretty much alone
at school and at home.
But here, they’re not alone.
So, it’s hard telling them not to come
to a place like this.
This… It’s gotten a little cold,
but if you'd like…
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Just a little something to share.
Welcome back.
I'm back.
There, a little something for you.
- Is that a seagull?
- What?
You could tell?
What kind of seagull is that?
There are 50 species
of seagulls in the world.
What, that many?
You don't even know that?
Hell, why do you even know that?
Seagulls are a man’s dream.
That's gotta be Jin Ichigaya's dream.
I mean, I’ve never heard anyone
say seagulls are a man’s dream.
Jin Ichigaya’s dream?
What’s that even supposed to mean?
Hey, sit over there for a sec.
What, why?
What's this about?
Come on…
SHAPING THE SOUNDS OF THE FUTURE
NO EXPERIENCE NEEDED! CRAFTSMEN WANTED
CONTACT INFORMATION
ADDRESS: NAGANO PREFECTURE
Alright, let’s make this nice and clean.
How’s the new home?
Are you glad this is your home?
What even is a home?
I don't even know anymore.
What do you think?
- What?
- Huh?
Who's that?
Who knows? At my age,
I’ve seen it all already.
Um, what are you doing here?
CURRENTLY CROWDFUNDING!
I couldn’t go home.
In the end…
I didn’t manage to collect
all the keychains.
I was chasing some silly dream,
thinking that if it came true,
I could be Hotaru’s mom again.
I…
clung to that dream like an idiot,
and in the end…
I failed.
I'm still…
a useless mom.
Maybe…
we might as well
give it all up, together.
What?
Right now,
I’m trying to buy a house with my partner,
but finding one that fits
all our conditions is tough.
Just once.
I was thinking maybe we should try
giving up in a positive way.
Want to try it together?
On three… two, one, together.
Whether it's an ideal home
or an ideal mom…
Let’s try giving up for real,
but in a positive way.
How so?
Then maybe
things will turn out better than expected.
What do you say?
Hotaru…
She is waiting for you.
Please come home to her.
We'll be waiting.
Wow, it looks just like him.
Even the worn-out look.
It's like he hasn’t showered in days.
It’s winter, so who cares?
But it doesn’t really feel
quite like Jin Ichigaya's dream, you know?
How about this?
What about this?
This has gotta be it, right?
Why don't we add one more man catcher?
Got it!
What?
Please forgive me!
Why are you running away!
Huh?
- What is he doing?
- I wonder…
Sorry!
I'm sorry!
I have a lot to say…
but welcome back, I guess.
Yes.
- He's staring at it.
- Right.
Yeah.
Didn't I just welcome you back?
- Welcome back!
Welcome back.
Remember our promise?
Three, two, one…
You're coming back home?
Yes.
Thank you for…
taking care of Hotaru.
It’s nothing.
I'm…
really thankful.
Don't mention it.
Everyone…
I’m really sorry for…
the inconvenience I caused.
Welcome home.
I'm back.
Miso soup…
There’s some left over from yesterday.
I'll have it.
Um, Sakuta.
What is it?
Can we talk for a moment?
- Let's eat.
- Thank you.
It's good.
I added in the secret ingredient.
TRUE MIRIN
I went shopping with Mr. Hatano.
I didn’t know you had to be 20
to buy true mirin. I was surprised.
I’m sorry…
I'm really…
sorry.
In the end…
I couldn’t even collect all the keychains…
Huh?
My bag was stolen
and so were the keychains.
And now…
I'm only left with just this.
NARA
I see.
With Nagano,
it would’ve been complete.
I won’t forgive you.
I love you, Mom,
but embezzling,
running away by yourself,
and never coming back?
I won't forgive you for that.
Just saying, "Have a good day"
every morning,
drinking miso soup
while saying, "It's good,"
or chatting and laughing before bed
about how our day went.
I’m happy…
just with that.
Sorry…
I'm sorry.
I really am…
Mom…
Your glasses…
You had them, right?
This will soak up all your tears.
What is this?
About the house…
What about it?
Maybe we should rethink it
from the beginning.
Why?
I realized that rather
than the house itself,
how we live together matters more.
Before we talk about
the house being a "clamp."
Is that really coming from you, Hatano?
Until now, I was so focused on buying
a house to keep us together.
I had to use the house as a "clamp"…
My head was full of thoughts like that.
But I absolutely don’t want to break up.
I won’t.
Okay.
We’ve already had plenty
of "clamps" in place anyway.
Such as our partnership,
the memories we made together,
this place, Inokashira Apartments,
and Hotaru.
Those things…
already exist.
I agree.
So, to feel at ease for once,
in a positive way…
I want to try giving things up.
Thank you for the food.
I’ve been thinking about that
for a while now…
Mr. Hatano plays the guitar,
and I came to like it
when I saw him do so.
So…
I tried making one myself.
You made this?
You’re a genius.
- You're exaggerating.
- No, really.
This is a masterpiece!
Are you going to give up
on the keychains, Mom?
Okay.
Yes?
What do you want?
Wait, why do you have that?
Huh?
If we just return it as is,
she won’t get arrested, right?
- Are you fine with that?
- Yeah, I’m tired.
I give up.
The car, the money, being a dad, or a man…
It’s all too much.
Somehow, I feel so light!
You didn’t use the money?
Nah.
Neither did I…
or anyone else.
- Is that how it is?
- Well then.
Wait, Dad!
I meant, former dad.
What is it?
You too, Mom.
I have…
one last request.
Good boy…
This feels more like home after all,
isn't that right?
- Um, maybe I shouldn’t be here after all.
- Please stay.
Together with me.
Okay.
- Thank you.
- Take care on the way out.
- Yes.
Next…
What's going on?
This is my mom,
former dad,
and my dad.
You're not wrong, but…
They’re all my guardians.
Okay then, before we get
to the main topic,
could you share your plans going forward?
- Right.
- Yes.
Uh-huh.
YEAR 3 CLASS 4 PARENT-TEACHER MEETING
Ma’am, what are your plans?
For now, I’m thinking
of turning myself in.
And after that?
I honestly have no idea what will happen.
But I did come to realize one thing.
- And what's that?
- Maybe
I can live just fine,
even without a dream.
Instead of chasing what I don’t have,
if I can cherish what I already have,
maybe that’s all I really need.
What kind of logic is that?
And what about you, sir?
I’m quitting being a dad.
You already did when we divorced.
You've never been a dad.
Details don’t matter.
I've got no money, nothing.
I’m done chasing a man’s dreams.
From now on,
I’ll chase Jin Ichigaya’s dream.
- Isn't that right?
- What do you even mean by that?
I still don’t really get it…
but, for starters, you know? That.
- What?
- What do I need to do again?
So that being alive feels good.
Ah, doing things
like smiling and greeting.
- Hello!
- Huh?
Like that, right?
- Hello!
- Hello.
You're doing great!
Don't mess with me!
Very well.
And you, Mr. Hatano?
Me? Uh, I…
want to buy a house
with Mr. Sakuta, someday.
Yeah, someday… Who knows when.
So, he's Hatano’s partner?
Yes, that's me.
So that's how it is.
We met thanks to Hotaru.
Really?
Is that right?
Hotaru brought you two together.
Well then, let’s get to the main topic.
It's about Hotaru’s career plans.
Have you decided on something?
I’m going to Nagano.
- Huh?
- What?
- Really?
CRAFTSMEN WANTED
I want to make guitars.
I want to work here.
So, you're not going to high school?
I don't know.
What do you mean?
In any case, I want to try this out first.
Even if I fail,
even if I end up on my own,
I think I can actually manage somehow.
Because even to a total stranger like me,
there are adults who are kind,
who help you,
who understand how you feel,
who care, I learned that.
You know,
all of you are completely
ridiculous adults.
One committed embezzlement
and left their kid alone
for some silly dream.
And here she is now,
claiming she can live
even without a dream.
One ignored me for years
and only acts like a dad
when it's convenient,
just for him to end up taking in a rabbit.
There are also those who might get fired,
might even get arrested,
but still pretended to be my parent.
I've come to learn that the world
has all kinds of weird adults.
Because of that…
I feel like I can become anything,
and I feel like I’ll be fine on my own.
No matter what happens,
I feel like I can pull through.
So…
To everyone here,
thank you very much.
I…
After graduating,
I’m going to Nagano by myself.
Feels a bit lonely, doesn’t it?
It's a bit early to say that.
But good for Hotaru, huh?
Yes.
Good for her.
We got called ridiculous adults, huh?
- You seem happy about it.
- Yes.
Just because I’m gay,
I’ve been living timidly
and held myself back.
And now,
getting called ridiculous?
Somehow, that makes me happy.
In the past,
I used to imagine
what life would’ve been like
if I weren’t gay.
Sakuta,
have you ever imagined what life
would be like if you weren’t gay?
Well…
Yeah, I have.
And?
I’m not telling.
Why are you asking all of a sudden?
Well, I was just remembering
something Hotaru asked me before.
"Is being gay hard?"
"Are you glad you’re gay?"
And what did you say?
"I want to believe I am,"
was what I said.
Okay.
And now…
I think I really am glad.
Me too.
Glad to hear that.
Yeah.
How cute!
Next.
- Huh?
- What?
A human?
Seems like it, yeah.
Humans indeed.
Another human.
- The same human?
- Looks like it.
But they aren't animals, right?
Well, humans are living creatures, though.
Okay then.
Yeah.
What, another human!
This person seems happy about something.
You're right.
Something good must've happened.
Yet another human.
- But there's a rabbit.
- Two…
living creatures then.
"I’m off to chase
Jin Ichigaya’s dream."
Make sure not to forget anything.
Good luck with the police today.
I might not be able to return for a while,
but I’ll cook meals
and put them in the fridge.
See you.
You too, Hotaru.
I’m off.
Nagano is really far after all.
Will she be okay alone?
Will she be eating proper meals?
Will she skip school
or walk around late at night?
Just thinking about it
makes my chest tight with worry.
She's just there
to check things out today.
You're right.
MARRIAGE REGISTRATION FORM
‪The food is ready.
Coming.
I’m ready!
- I'll be off now.
- See you.
- Bye!
- Then,
- I'm counting on you.
- Sure.
- Matsumoto City, Nagano Prefecture…
- Okay.
- Sasaga.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
- Take care.
Subtitle translation by: Jeffery